Behan Family papers 1883-1944 (bulk 1907-1944)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Behan Family papers, 1883-1944 (bulk 1907-1944)
AZ 011
Behan family
Personal and official correspondence, financial records, notes, a photograph album, and photographs relating chiefly to personal and family life.
0.8 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Pioneer Arizona family, prominent in public service and law enforcement. John Behan, 1845-1912, was county deputy sheriff at Tombstone, Ariz., 1879-1881, then became first county sheriff when Cochise County was created in 1881. He served as sheriff of several other Arizona counties during his career. He also served as Chinese Inspector, 1896-1897; worked in government service, in Cuba during the War of 1898, and in China during the Boxer Rebellion; and as business manager of the Tucson Citizen, 1901-1911. Julia Behan was his sister. Albert P. Behan, his son, worked for the U.S. Customs Service along the Mexican border, 1913-1928.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Behan Family Papers, 1883-1944
Series II: Photographs, ca. 1890-1940
Scope and Content Note
Personal and official correspondence, financial records, notes, a photograph album, and photographs relating chiefly to personal and family life. Includes approximately 100 photographs of family members; most are studio portraits. A photograph album contains snapshots of Julia Behan, her family and friends, in California, 1907-1924. Also present is a diary of John Behan's railway travels, expenses, and inspections while a Chinese Inspector, 1896-1897; and account books and journals from Albert Behan's customs work.
Access Terms
Behan, John Harris, 1845-1912
Behan, Albert P., 1873-
Behan family -- Photographs
Smuggling -- United States -- History -- Sources
Customs administration -- United States -- History -- Sources
Chinese -- Arizona
United States -- Emigration and immigration -- History -- Sources
Albums
Correspondence
Journals
Container List
- Series I: Behan Family Papers, 1883-1944
  - John H. Behan: letters and miscellaneous material. 1883-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains several account record books, railroad passes and membership cards; a legal document appointing John. H. Behan as Railway Policeman for the Southern Pacific Company; miscellaneous personal and business correspondence. Also contains a section of letters from "Bert."
  - John H. Behan: "Chinese Inspector," notebook. 1896-1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains one leather bound diary with notes about Behan's railway travels, expenses and inspections. The diary is inscribed, "John H. Behan, Chinese Inspector."
  - Albert P. Behan: letters and miscellaneous material. 1908-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contains mainly miscellaneous personal correspondence received by Albert P. Behan.
  - Albert P. Behan: Customs collector on Mexican border. 1913-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Contains several small account books and journals from Albert P. Behan's work with the U.S. Customs Service along the Mexican border, plus a Treasury Department manual for the Guidance of the Outdoor Force of the Customs Service. Also contains several letters on Treasury Department letterhead.
  - Albert P. Behan: miscellaneous financial records. 1914-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Contains several small ban account record books and other bank records, plus miscellaneous papers relating to personal property.
  - Julia M. Behan: will, estate papers. 1931-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Contains will, and estate papers of Julia M. Behan, and a letter from the California Trust company to Albert T. Behan regarding same, dated 1936. Also contains a handwritten bill of sale from a gallery in Florence, Italy.
- Series II: Photographs, ca. 1890-1940
  - Behan Family: photo album, and letter from Mrs. Nancy Behan Meeker. 1907-1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: miscellaneous photographs, mainly portraits of Behan family members. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: unidentified. (Box 2, Folder 3-4)